# Syed Atif Ahmed



+92 322 2861659 | satif04@gmail.com

### Sr. Technical Consultant | Partner Seller Microsoft

Sr. Technical Consultant on Linux and Microsoft Technologies. Offering 11 years of managerial and technical background on Linux and Microsoft Solutions. Atif is seasoned enterprise level Systems Architect who is Specializing in domestic and global deployment along with migrations of SCCM and Microsoft Intune. He has designed, planned and Implemented Infrastructure Projects throughout Pakistan, Middle East and West African Regions and hands on live production experience with some of the complex environments.

## **Accomplishments:**

- Presented Microsoft Intune and SCCM Live Demos at Pearl Continental Karachi
- Conducted SCCM Current Branch Boot Camp at Onwire Technologies
- Presented Azure Site Recovery Live Showcase Demo at Pearl Continental Karachi
- Presented Operation Management Suite and Advance Threat Analytics at Mövenpick Karachi
- Conducted Microsoft Windows 10 Bootcamp at NED University Of Engineering & Technology.
- Hosted a Workshop on SCCM for "Capacity Building of IT Staff" in HEC Head Office (Islamabad) published including in the HEC News & Views Magazine.
- SCCM deployment and migration projects from ranging several 100 to over 25,000 users.
- MTN Nigeria SCCM and BDD Deployment Project Team Lead

# **Areas of Expertise:**

- Leadership and Team Building
- Project Management
- Live Demo Presentations
- SCCM and Intune Deployment and Migrations
- Enterprise Infrastructure Projects Implementations
- Systems Administration
- Training and Mentoring
- Vendor Management
- UAT Management
- Advance Web Development
- Virtualization
- Cyber Security and Ethical Hacking
- Digital Marketing and Branding
- Headhunting

## **Key Competencies Domains:**

- SCCM and Intune
- Cloud based platforms such as Azure and AWS
- Cloud based solutions such as Enterprise Mobility+Security and Microsoft OMS Solutions
- CMS such as WordPress & Joomla
- Extensive knowledge of Linux Platform including Ubuntu, CentOS, OpenSUSE, Kali Linux, Black Arch, Parrot Security, Backbox Linux, Fedora, Red Hat Enterprise, Linux Mint, Arch Linux, Manjaro Linux, Revenge OS, Deepin OS, Solus and Elementary OS and many more
- Virtualization using Microsoft Hyper V,VMware and Citrix XenDesktop
- Windows Server 2003/2008/2012/2016 Infrastructure Design
- Windows 7/8/10 desktop engineering & deployment using (SCCM,BDD & MDT)
- Microsoft AD Design & Implementation
- NLB & Failover Clustering
- Feasibility/Requirements Analysis
- Ethical Hacking
- Out of the box Research & Implementation
- Advance Web Development

# **Professional Experience**

#### PARTNER SELLER MICROSOFT | MICROSOFT | MAY 2017 - PRESENT

- *Drive a strong co-sell motion with Microsoft.*
- Access to exclusive content and deep engagement with Microsoft teams
- Unique access to Microsoft Full Time Employee (FTE) enablement and the Microsoft-endorsed Partner Seller credential.
- Invited on Partner Seller Meetups, Trainings and Conferences
- Full Access to the Microsoft Corporate Network

#### SENIOR TECHNICAL CONSULTANT | IOP | NOV 2016 - JULY 2018

Responsible for detailed Plan, Design and Implementation of System Center Solutions for prospective customers and also provide cloud-based solution on Microsoft Azure Platform such as EMS, OMS, Azure Site Recovery and Azure Backup.

#### SENIOR INFRASTRUCTURE CONSULTANT | KALSOFT LIMITED | OCT 2013 - MAR 2014

- Responsible of SCCM Planning and Deployment
- Provide SCCM Technical Proposals with extensive solutions
- Research and Implementation of upcoming products

#### MICROSOFT CONSULTANT | MHD INFOTECH LLC | OCT 2012 - SEP 2013

- Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center 2012 Suite throughout Oman Region.
- Responsible for formal sign off on all System Center Project deliverables
- Responsible for Bill All Signed-off Microsoft Infrastructure Projects throughout Oman Region
- Responsible for Pre-Sales and Post-Sales of System Center Suite throughout Oman Region
- Responsible for Meeting with Prospective Clients
- Responsible for delivering RFP, Techincal Proposal as per requirement of prospective customers

#### TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST | IOP | MAR 2012 - AUG 2012

Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center 2012 Suite throughout Pakistan Region.

#### TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST | METALSOFT | NOV 2010 - FEB 2012

Provided pre-sales, post-sales and technical support for regional customers accompanied sales staff on meetings with prospective customers to discuss the viability and feasibility of the proposed solution and/or upcoming opportunities.

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER (PERN2) | HIGHER EDUCATION COMMISSION | SEP 2009 - SEP 2010

Responsible for the Designing, Planning and Implementation of Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager throughout PERN2 Network.

#### INFRASTRUCTURE SERVICES CONSULTANT | KALSOFT LIMITED | NOV 2006 - JAN 2009

- Responsible for all the problems resolutions pertaining to ongoing projects.
- Handled all escalations related to the IT Projects.
- *Meetings with prospective customers to discuss the viability and feasibility of the proposed solution.*

#### SYSTEMS INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER | KALSOFT LIMITED | MAY 2006 - NOV 2009

- Research and Implementation of upcoming Microsoft products
- Create, change, and delete user accounts per request.
- Repair and recover from hardware or software failures.
- Coordinate and communicate with impacted constituencies.
- Apply OS patches and upgrades on a regular basis, and upgrade administrative tools and utilities.
- Configure / add new services as necessary.
- *Perform ongoing performance tuning, hardware upgrades, and resource optimization as required.*
- Configure CPU, memory, and disk partitions as required.
- *Maintain data center environmental and monitoring equipment.*

# **Technology Summary**

Languages: HTML, CSS, Java Script, C,C++, Java, Visual Basic, Python

Software Products: SCCM, SCVMM, ATA, SCOM, VMware Workstation, VMware vSphere, BDD, MDT, Citrix

Xen Desktop

**Systems:** Unix, Linux, Windows, Mac OS X

Databases: MS SQL, My SQL, Maria DB, Oracle, Access

# **Projects Summary**

- Microsoft M365 Security and Compliance Workshop (Pearl Continental Karachi)
- Deployment of Microsoft Advance Threat Analytics At International Office Products
- Conducted Two Days Bootcamp on Planning and Deployment Of SCCM Current Branch 1606 At Onwire Technologies
- Designing, Planning and Deployment of System Center Configuration Manager At Confiz Limited Data Center (Lahore)

- Microsoft OMS Solutions POC At Shirazi Trading
- Linux LAMP Based Portal Migration from Linux Mint 17.2 to Linux Mint 18.2
- Operation Management Suite Implementation At Toyota Indus Motors Company Limited
- Deployment of Microsoft Advance Threat Analytics
- Microsoft Azure POC at Marie Stopes International
- MCSE Server Infrastructure Training For CTTC Pvt Limited
- Purchase and Supplier Order Management System App 2.2 For MaShaAllah Super Store
- Planning and Implementation of CentOS, SAMBA, SSH,SFTP Servers
- VPN Setup and Configurations at LyncSoft
- Dynamic Web Portal Server using LAMP Stack Deployment at LyncSoft
- Envisioning, Planning, Designing SCCM and SCOM Enterprise solution for Bank Alfalah Limited.
- The Pakistan Air Force SCCM Corporate Training Islamabad
- MHD InfoTech LLC Oman (Muscat)
- Daleel Petroleum LLC Oman (Muscat)
- Majan Electricity Company (Muscat)
- Higher College Of Technology Oman (Muscat)
- Higher Education Commission (Islamabad)
- Sultan Qaboos University Oman (Muscat)
- Qatar Govt Ministries (Doha)
- Ministry Of Education Oman (Muscat)
- MTN Communication Pvt Ltd (Nigeria Lagos)
- Deputy Commissioner Office Islamabad (CDCO)
- KalSoft Lahore Training
- Ministry Of Foreign Affairs (Islamabad)
- Designing & Implementing An Infrastructure Solution for KKI (Phase II)
- Designing & Implementing An Infrastructure Solution for KKI (Phase I)
- Implementing Electrol Unit Management System & Wireless LAN For Election Commission Of Pakistan

#### **Education**

# BS (COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING) | APRIL 2002-2006 | SIR SYED UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

- *Graduated with BS in Computer Systems Engineering.*
- Final Year Project Lead and was Team Leader through out all semesters.
- Major focused on Operating Systems, Computer Systems & Networks.
- Received Merit Scholarship.

# **Professional Certifications/Licenses**

CEH Coursework

Introduction to Linux

Linux System Administration

Microsoft Specialist - Configuring Windows Devices

**MCSE** 

**MCTS** 

MCP

**CCNA**